Homesteading is a little different than
you think. A lot of people say they want
to live off grid.
>> You think it's all sunshine and
rainbows, but they have absolutely no
idea what it'd be like.
>> Damn man, you wake up to like water
not coming out of the pipe.
>> going to go through and show you what a
day in my life looks like.
>> The goat having to be fed, the chickens
having to be caught, and see if you
think you could live this off-grid life,
too. Once again, no water from the
mangeta. This is our food. This is what
we eat. So, this is a fair amount of
importance. Mangeta is a 2-mi long pipe
that the Costa Ricans used to take water
from the river. Made it to the river,
and we got to pick it up.
Yeah, that's too light. There's barely
any pressure. The box might just be
dirty.
>> We have to follow the whole 2 mi to
figure it out.
>> dedication to the cause. We're climbing
through the water pipe
to try and get to the other side so the
lobsters won't die. Now, I think it'd be
easier just to buy food from the store,
but far less rewarding.
Hombre.
Huh?
Hey! Got a problem with all the baby
chickens getting out. So, we have
fashioned all this right here to keep
them in.
And Alex built damn near this whole
thing by herself here for the baby
chickens. Just going to put them in
right here. They'll have a space to go
in with the bigger chickens so we can
make our own eggs. We got the baby
chickens in there. You can see them
doing their little chicken things. We
got chickens in the solar room. Go. Go.
Go.
>> [laughter]
>> Oh, good God almighty.
Homesteading is wild.
>> Whipping up some chorreadas, fresh corn.
Then we take it and blend it right here,
make it into a batter, and fry it in the
pan. This is what it looks like all
done. Mhm.
Damn it. A bolt came out of this when we
were driving, and the fan shroud was
rocking all around. Damn near left us on
the side of the road. Nobody to call but
you. Is that a donkey or horse? No, that
was a horse. That's a little baby horse.
These are date nights now, walking
barefooted and looking at baby horses in
Costa Rica. Finishing up the 14-hour
work day with this, a 60-ft run of
number four copper through a concrete
wall with three 90s coming over here to
feed the rest of the farm off the solar.
240, there we go. 120. 120. Hell yeah.
So, you think you want to live this
life? You want to go off grid? It's more
work than you'd ever expect. I ain't
some influencer out here selling you a
dream. I'm showing you what it takes to
live a life like this. It is nothing but
work, focus, dedication, and intention.
But, I still tell you, chase your
dreams. It's worth it.